贝克特
Beckett?
该吃早点了
Breakfast time.
哇  我是做了什么能修来这等福分
Oh. What did I do to deserve this,
当然  除了保持真我之外
Other than, you know, being me?
这还不足够么
Isn't that enough?
说吧  你有什么企图
Okay, what do you want?
没什么  我为什么要有企图啊
Nothing. Why do I have to want something?
1999年3月
March 1999,
你想要个Hello Kitty的背包
you wanted a hello kitty backpack.
你就给我做了一个
I got French toast with
带着奶油泡沫笑脸的法国土司
a whipped cream smiley face.
2004年10月  你想要一套崭新的
October 2004, you wanted a set of mint condition
"帝国反击战"里的光剑
"Empire strikes back" Lightsabers.
你就做了一个形状像达斯·维德的煎蛋饼
I got an omelet shaped like Darth Vader.
好吧  我想要一辆摩托车
Okay. I want a vespa.
是小型摩托车  我的朋友们都有
It's a scooter. All my friends have them,
有了它出行就方便多了
and it would make getting around the city so much easier,
-而且绝对安全  -宝贝儿
- and they're totally safe. - Honey.
我保证一定戴安全帽  绝对不在夜里开
I'll always wear a helmet, and I'll never drive at night.
你知道我是很有责任心的
You know how responsible I am.
我倒不是对你不放心
It's not you I'm worried about.
但是在纽约开车
Driving in new york,
就像是拍电影"疯狂的麦克斯"
it's like a-a mad max movie.
爸  我真的很想要
Dad, I really want this.
你至少考虑一下嘛
Will you at least think about it?
好不好嘛
Please.
好吧  我会考虑的
Yes, I will think about it
如果你让我安安静静的
if you leave me alone
享用完我的早餐
so that I can finish my breakfast.
没问题
Deal.
啊  是贝克特
Ah, it's Beckett.
还记得上次你吃的太饱之后
Uh... Remember what happened
去罪案现场的后果吗
last time you went to a crime scene on a full stomach?
想起来了吧
Yeah.
卡塞尔
Castle.
今天谁这么不幸中了头奖
And who is the unlucky winner today?
迪昂·卡福
Deon Carver,
一个保释代理人
bail bondsman.
这是他的办公室
This is his office.
昨天晚上他遭遇了强行入室抢劫
He walked into a b&e last night,
还没来得及用自己注册过的枪
and before he had a chance to use his registered firearm,
凶手就用奖杯打他的头把他放倒了
our killer knocked him over the head with that.
神枪手奖杯
A sharpshooter award.
这怎么看都很具有讽刺意味啊
That is ironic on so many levels.
啊不  只在两个方面很讽刺
No, just two.
凶手在卡福的血迹里
Our killer left a partial shoe print
留下了不完整的鞋印
in Carver's blood,
很可能是在处理奖杯上的指纹时留下的
probably while wiping the trophy clean.
鞋印不完整  所以很难判断尺码
Shoe print isn't complete enough to tell the size,
但是鞋底的纹路应该很容易辨认
but the tread mark should be easy to identify.
在离开之前  凶手很善良地
And then before leaving, our killer was nice enough
拨打了911  听筒没有放回去
to call 9-1-1 and leave the phone off the hook.
凶手内心受到谴责了
Someone was feeling a little guilty?
没有那么内疚  电话是11点打来的
Not too guilty. The call came in at 11:00.
而据我估计死亡时间是10点
I'm estimating time of death around 10:00.
也就是说凶手
Which means our perp
有大约一个小时的时间洗劫这里
had about an hour to ransack the place.
想要找什么呢
Looking for what?
钱财吗  我是说
Um, money? I mean,
保释代理人经常接受现金支付
bail bondsmen often get paid in cash.
一千万的现金足够成为
And 10% of a million
将这里洗劫一空的理由了
would be enough reason to tear up a place.
莱恩和埃斯波西托正在找
Ryan and Esposito are taking a look around the building
看大楼有没有监控设备
for any security cameras.
没有任何监控设备
That's a negative on cameras.
为什么一个计算器会造成信号干扰呢
Why would a calculator cause feedback?
这不是计算器
It's not a calculator.
是窃听器
It's a bug.
确切地说是无限R.F.发射器
A wireless R.F. Transmitter to be precise.
不要把这和
Not to be confused
更先进的红外信号成套设备弄混
with the more advanced infrared signal burst device.
写小说做的调查
Book research?
保姆摄像机
Nanny cam.
那么  你认为凶手是以抢劫做掩饰
So... Do you think that the robbery
来安装窃听器
was just a pretense for the placement of the bug,
结果被当场发现了吗
and then the killer was caught in the act?
卡塞尔  这又不是水门事件
Well, it's not Watergate, Castle.
如果凶手意图是
If the point was
为了要窃听卡福的办公室
to bug Carver's office,
那为什么卡福死了
then why leave it here
还要把窃听器留下呢
once he's dead?
那你告诉我  万事通小姐
Well, tell me this, Miss know-it-all.
什么人会这么想要
Mm-hmm. Who would want to
窃听一个保释代理人的信息呢
bug a burly bail bondsman so badly?
好
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
窃听器不是来自执法机构
So it's not law enforcement
也不是来自联调局中情局之类的
or a 3-letter agency.
那窃听器是一个商用器材
That bug was a commercial device.
我联系了泰国的制造商
I contacted the manufacturer in Thailand.
他们正在调查序列号
They're looking up the serial number
查明货物送达的商店地点
to see what store it was shipped to,
希望从他们那
and hopefully from there,
能得到购买人的消息
we should find out who bought it.
想当年杀手们都还是支持美国货的
I remember when killers used to buy American.
我在新联邦数据库
Yo, I ran the shoe print through
调查了凶手的鞋印
the new federal database.
和这些平底鞋的花纹相吻合
They matched the tread mark to these loafers here.
这些流苏
Ah, the no-hassle tassel.
在1984年十分流行
These were the height of fashion... in 1984.
这些是和卡福有过暴力过往的
These are photos of all of Carver's clients
所有客户的名单
with a history of violence.
到卡福的大楼周围分发一下这些照片
Can you show them around his building,
看有没有人昨天去过那里
see if anyone was there yesterday?
是  遵命
Yeah, you got it.
你也曾经有过青葱岁月
You were a girl once.
现在依旧年轻
Still am.
能不能告诉我为什么
Can you tell me why
我女儿这么想要一个小摩托车呢
my daughter wants one of these so badly?
女孩儿们意识到自己
Well, bikes are
不可能拥有小马驹的时候
what girls want
就会想要辆摩托车
when we realize we're never gonna get a pony.
-你有吗  -现在还有
- Did you have one? - I still do.
94年的哈雷软尾
'94 Harley Softail.
为了买它整个高中都在打工挣钱
Worked all of high school to pay for it.
你父母怎么看
And how did your parents feel about it?
我爸威胁要把我送到修道院
Well, my dad threatened to send me to a nunnery.
我妈只是摇着头说
And my mom just shook her head and said,
"凯蒂  你每次骑车的时候
"Katie, every time you ride that thing,
只要记着你是多么讨厌我说
just remember how much you hate
'不听老人言  吃亏在眼前'"
hearing me tell you 'I told you so.'"
你知道这意味着什么吧
You know what this means, though, don't you?
不知道  意味什么
No, what?
阿丽克西斯已经进入了她的叛逆期了
Well, Alexis is entering her wild-child phase.
我女儿吗  不会的
My daughter? Nah. I don't think so.
是的  卡塞尔
Oh, yeah, Castle.
所有女孩儿都会经历这个阶段
All girls go through it.
好女孩儿情况尤其严重
And good girls are the worst.
其实  我还记得有一次...
In fact, I remember this one time when...
-有新发现吗  -是的
- Hey, did you find anything? - Yeah.
我们找到了卡福的老婆
We located Carver's wife
布鲁克
Brooke.
在她霍博肯的姐姐那里
She's visiting her sister in Hoboken.
警察正在把她带来
Uniforms are on their way to pick her up now.
还有蕾妮打电话说
Oh, and Lanie called.
她发现了奇怪的东西
She said she found something weird.
我清理尸体时
I found this hidden in Carver's sock
在卡福的袜子里发现了这个
while I was stripping the body.
这到底是什么东西
What the hell is it?
我不知道  你才是侦探
I don't know. You're the detective.
可能是凶手在卡福办公室
Maybe it's what our killer was looking for
想要找的东西
in Carver's office.
你不是开玩笑吧  这个东西吗
Seriously? That?
是啊  这很可能是一些什么
Yeah. Well, it's probably
复杂的密码或者是什么...
some complex code or a--
世界上最无聊的涂鸦吗
The world's least-interesting doodle?
这可不值当去杀人
It's not something that you kill a guy over.
那为什么卡福要藏起来呢
Then why did he hide it?
我告诉过我老公
I told my husband,
他每天和那些野蛮人打交道
the kind of animals he dealt with every day,
迟早会出事的
something bad was gonna happen.
卡福夫人  你老公最近有没有
Mrs. Carver, had your husband had any troubles
和什么客户有过节呢
with any of his clients recently?
迪昂不怎么和我谈工作上的事情
Deon didn't talk about work a lot with me.
但是他昨天确实说过
Oh, but he did say
他最近要把某个人给保释出来
that he had to straighten someone out yesterday.
他说事情已经变得很棘手
He said it got pretty ugly.
知道有可能是谁吗
Any idea who?
对不起  我不知道
I'm sorry, no.
你老公在办公室放现金吗
Did your husband keep cash in his office?
不放
Uh, no.
他一直坚持收汇票或者银行本票
He insisted on money orders and cashier's checks.
他心肠很好  但是他并不蠢
He had a good heart, but he wasn't stupid.
我们在你老公的袜子里
We found this
找到了这个东西
folded up in your husband's sock.
知道这是什么吗
Any idea what it is?
我从来没见过
I've never seen this before.
她虽然没认出来这个东西
Just because she doesn't recognize it
但这并不意味着就不重要
doesn't mean it's not important.
布鲁克甚至都承认
Brooke even admitted...
卡福从来
Carver never
不和她谈工作上的事情
talked to her about work.
卡塞尔
Castle.
我只是说我的蜘蛛侠直觉
I'm just saying, my spidey sense
非常强烈的在感知我
is tingling about this.
我不能把整个谋杀调查
Well, I can't base an entire murder investigation
建立在你的蜘蛛侠直觉上
on your spidey senses.
为什么不呢
Why not?
凶手在找什么东西
Our killer was looking for something.
而我们的受害者在藏着什么东西
Our victim was hiding something.
[拉丁语]意思是说
Res ipsa loquitur. It means--
"事实不言自明"
"The thing speaks for itself."
我知道  我只是说
I know. All I'm saying
即使卡福没有在办公室放现金
is that even though Carver didn't keep cash in his offices,
但这也并不能证明这
it doesn't mean that
不是一起蓄意入室抢劫案
it wasn't an attempted robbery.
我是说  我们说的
I mean, these aren't mensa members
又不是一些超级高智商的人
we're talking about.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
卡福大楼的女服务员说
Waitress at, uh, the diner in Carver's building
昨天晚上她看见了
said that she saw
卡福和他的一个客户
Carver and one of his clients
吵了起来
get into a shouting match last night.
这人叫兰登·皮尔斯
Some skell named Random Pierce.
竟然有人给自己的孩子
Somebody actually
起名字叫兰登
named their kid Random?
怪不得走上了犯罪之路呢
No wonder he turned to a life of crime.
兰登刚在五点监狱服完两年刑
Random just did two years at five points correctional
出来一个星期以后  又因入室抢劫被捕
and a week after he got out, he was arrested for a b&e.
听起来这消息很管用
That sounds like a real winner.
服务员说听到
Waitress said that
兰登告诉卡福说
she heard him tell Carver
如果不把东西给他
that if he didn't give it back
兰登就自己去拿
that Random was gonna take it.
我很想知道这个"东西"到底是什么
Hmm. Well, I wonder what "It" could be.
兰登今天早晨
So Random had a court hearing
本该有一场庭审的
scheduled for this morning.
他没去
He didn't show.
已经在上午9点申请了对他的拘捕令
They issued a bench warrant for his arrest at 9:00 A.M.
我们去带他回来
Let's go pick him up.
兰登最后的居住地就是这里
This was Random's last known address.
好了  你们哥俩去后面包抄
All right, you guys take the back.
你的哈雷摩托车
So this Harley of yours,
有照片吗
do you have any pictures?
当然有
Uh, yeah, I do.
但是我都不会给你看的
But I'm not gonna be showing any of them to you.
为什么不呢
Why not?
我想你应该难以接受
Well, because I don't think you can handle the sight of me
我穿着紧身黑色皮衣跨在车上的样子
straddling it in tight black leather.
我绝不会给我女儿买摩托车的
I'm so not getting a scooter for my daughter.
是兰登
That's Random.
纽约警察  站住
NYPD, stop!
我酝酿这个动作很久了耶
I've always wanted to do that!
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
这是我的犯人
That's my suspect.
放轻松  我们是自家人
Okay, relax. We're on the same team.
罗伊
Royce?
丫头
Hey, kid.
好久不见了
Long time.
是啊  太久了
Yeah, too long.
-开车技术不错  -谢谢
- Nice driving. - Aw, thanks.
迈克·罗伊
Mike Royce,
赏金猎人
bounty hunter. Boom.
理查德·卡塞尔  作家
Ah, Richard Castle, the writer.
罗伊曾经是个警察
Royce used to be on the job.
"曾经是个警察"
"On the job"?
她把我说的和其他普通警察一样
She says that like I'm any cop.
我是她毕业之前的教官
I was her training officer when she left the academy.
各位  要是我打扰了你们的重聚
Hey, if I'm imposing on your happy reunion
我可以离开的
You know, I could just go.
你要去的地方只有监狱
The only place you're goin' is jail.
翻译：东方  大卫熊  深深  千花
时间轴：零    后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：安小七
听我说  我认识一个人
You know, I-I know a guy
可以帮你修理汽车凹痕
that'll get that dent out of your car.
放了我  我一个电话就搞定
You let me go, I'll give him a call.
闭嘴  进去吧
Shut up and get in the box.
怪不得那个家伙会逃掉
No wonder that guy was getting away.
-看看你的鞋子  -什么
- Look at your shoes. - What?
这跟到底是几英寸高啊
How many inches are those heels?
我的鞋子没问题
My shoes are fine,
他也没跑掉
and he wasn't getting away.
怎么会有人出钱让你去抓兰登
So how'd you get the bounty on Random?
我在法院有个朋友
I got a buddy at the courthouse.
兰登庭审缺席
Random missed his hearing,
我就接到了这个活
I got a call.
你怀疑他谋杀
So you like this guy for murder.
是的  谋杀他的保证人
Huh? Yeah, for his bail bondsman--
迪昂·卡福
Deon Carver.
天啊  我认识迪昂
God, I know Deon.
去年我还为他追踪过别人
I just did a skip trace for him last year.
我们在他的袜子里
You know, we found
找到了一张奇怪的纸
a weird piece of paper in his sock.
我想是某种代码
I'm thinking it's some kind of code.
人们会为了一张纸而去杀人的
Only paper I've seen people kill for
只有美钞
had dead presidents on it.
听着
Look,
如果兰登不是你们要找的人
if Random's not your guy,
我能不能带他回去交差
can I take him over to central booking,
拿我的酬金
collect my bounty?
当然没问题  如果他有不在场证据
Yeah, sure, if he alibis out,
但要换了我就不会抱什么希望
But I wouldn't hold my breath on that.
卡塞尔  你来不来
Castle, you coming?
我还是和罗伊一起吧
Oh, actually, I was gonna hang back with royce,
听他讲讲以前的美好的故事
Hear some stories about the good ol' days.
随便你吧
Okay. Fine.
但你要告诉他卡拉ok监视的那件事
But if you tell him about the karaoke stakeout,
我就把你的有关猴子的故事告诉他
I'm gonna tell him what happened with the monkey.
我会严守秘密的
My lips are sealed.
但是我好有一箩筐其他的故事
But I got a lot of other stories.
我没有逃跑
I wasn't running away.
我只是在慢跑
I was jogging.
那你好端端从大楼上
So what were you doing climbing down
爬下来干什么
the side of a building?
混合训练  对心血管有更好的锻炼效果
Cross-training. Better cardiovascular workout.
兰登  你在五点监狱服过刑
Random, you did a stint at five points correctional
放出来不到一周
and within a week of your release,
你就闯入了别人的公寓
you were breaking in to someone's apartment.
那是个误会
That was a misunderstanding.
我把我朋友的地址写错了
I wrote down my friend's address wrong.
是吗
Really?
那你把迪昂·卡福杀了怎么解释
So what do you call killing Deon Carver,
认错人了吗
mistaken identity?
迪昂死了
Deon's dead?
你就装吧  你有破门而入的前科
Nice try. You have a history of breaking and entering,
卡福办公室被翻了个底朝天
and I have a victim whose offices were ransacked,
有证人看到被害人与你发生争吵
and you were seen arguing with Carver
三个小时后他被杀
three hours before he was killed.
他请我吃饭  因为他想要强调那天早上
He invited me to dinner 'cause he wanted to stress
我在法庭上出席的重要性
the importance of my attendance in court this morning.
我不出席他要被罚款10万美圆
And seeing as he had 100k on the hook if skipped--
你的确没出席
Which you did.
我闹表没响
My alarm clock didn't go off.
我看你是因为杀了卡福太疲倦
Or you were so exhausted after killing Carver
-才睡过头的吧  -拜托
- that you slept right through it. - Come on!
我们吃过饭后三个小时
Three hours after we had dinner,
我在市中心的书店偷书呢
I was shoplifting at book mart uptown--
你杀了人
You threatened someone's life and then
然后跑去偷书
decide to shoplift a book?
我那是忘了付钱
That's why I forgot to pay.
我在监狱的图书馆呆习惯了
I was so used to being in the prison library.
我想和保安说明白的
I tried to tell the security dude that,
但他使出忍者锁喉术之类的抓住了我
but he had me in some ninja choke hold.
幸好我机灵
Luckily for me,
在警察来之前溜走了
I was able to slip away before the cops came.
衰人  但是那个保安绝对会记得我
Sucker. But that guard would totally remember me.
她一个手拿着猫
So now she's got the cat in one hand,
枪在另一只手
her gun in the other.
我拼了命给她让出地方
I'm trying to get the hell outta the way
好让她毙了那个拿着鱼枪的家伙
so she can shoot the guy with the speargun.
不过罗伊总是挡道  每次我
Except Royce has such a giant head, that every time
扣动扳机的时候  我总是在想
I go to pull the trigger, all I can think about is
要是真的打伤他
how much paperwork I'll have to do
我要写多少报告才能脱身
if accidentally shoot him.
-你知道她做什么了吗  -什么
- Yeah, okay, so you know what she does? - What?
她跟那家伙说你把鱼枪放下
She offers to show the guy her
我就给你看咪咪
boobs if he drops the speargun.
-他放下了吗  -你给他看了吗
- Did he? - Did you?
没有  因为他和你们一样
No, 'cause he had the same slack-jawed look
嘴都合不上  口水直流
that the two of you have.
正好给了我机会将他制服
Allowing me to take the guy down,
但是那个时候我想明白了一件事
but I'll tell you what I realized in that moment--
和贝克特一起工作
With Beckett,
你要随时做好一切准备
you gotta be ready for anything.
天啊  我今天算是见识了别样的你
Wow. I'm seeing a whole new side of you today.
而且不介意你再多展示点
And--and feel free to show me more.
看你干的好事  你怎么能给他吃这种甜头
Do you see what happens when you feed the animals?
看起来那个小偷
Hey. So it looks like your shoplifter
还真不是我们的凶手
isn't our killer after all.
书店的保安确认他抓到他
Guard at book mart confirmed that he caught him
试图偷一本
trying to steal a copy
《达芬奇密码》
of "The Da Vinci Code."
"The Da Vinci Code."
也许他认为那本书能帮他解密那份文件
Maybe he thought it could help him decipher the document,
认为那是某种古宗教的密码
thinking it's some kind of an ancient religious cryptogram
预言即将到来的僵尸末日
prophesizing the coming zombie apocalypse.
他总是这样吗
He always like this?
通常他都是围绕中情局阴谋论
No, it's usually about CIA conspiracies.
我的理论很靠谱的
I was really close on one of those.
你想让我们把兰登关起来吗
So do you want us to lock Random up?
书店希望我们扣押他
The store wants us to hold on to him.
我们还是让罗伊把他带到中央警局吧
Why don't we let Royce take him down to central?
-书店的人可以在那里起诉他  -好的
- Book mart can press charges over there. - All right.
谢了丫头  我欠你人情
Thanks, kid. I owe you one.
你什么都不欠我
You don't owe me anything,
你懂的
And you know it.
帮个忙  帮我们拍张照片
Hey, do me a favor. Take a picture.
没问题
Yeah, yeah, of course.
来吧  重逢总要照张相
Thanks. Come on. Old time's sake.
好的
Okay.
-不错  -很高兴见到你
- Nice. - It was so good to see you.
你要时刻警觉  丫头
You stay sharp, kid.
里克  可别让她对你"颐指气使"太久
Rick, don't let her boss you around too much.
走吧  小子  我们去中央关押局吧
Hey, come on, kitten. We got a date at central booking.
他故事讲得真不错
He tells a terrific story.
基情荡漾了吗  卡塞尔
You got a little bromance there, castle?
什么  没有啦
What? No. What?
没什么大不了的  他本来就让人无法抗拒
It's all right. He is pretty hard to resist.
罗伊和贝克特后来为什么不搭档了
Why didn't, uh, Royce and Beckett stay partners?
她升官了  他退休了
She moved up, and he moved out.
干了20年  递交了辞呈
He did his 20 and put in his papers.
我想他是意识到
I think he realized that
他永远不会像她那么出色
he wasn't gonna do any better than her.
我认为贝克特是对的
I think Beckett's right about this.
这个看起来真的没有什么价值
This doesn't look like anything worth killing for.
除非那是光明会失传的秘密
Unless it's the lost secret to the illuminati...
或是摩斯密码
or morse code.
不是  全是线  没有点
Negative. All dashes, no dots.
伙计们  想听听奇怪的线索吗
Hey, guys. You wanna hear something weird?
在卡福办公室找到了
We got a fingerprint hit from Carver's office
一个惯犯克利福德·斯塔奇的指纹
on a longtime felon named Clifford Stuckey.
斯塔奇
Stuckey?
为什么我会记得这个名字
Why do I know that name?
因为兰登出狱后
That's because it was Stuckey's apartment
闯入的就是斯塔奇的公寓
that Random broke in to when he got out of prison.
肯定不是巧合
That can't be a coincidence.
克利福德·斯塔奇
Clifford Stuckey.
纽约警察  开门
NYPD. Open up.
你是谁
Who are you?
纽约警察
NYPD.
你是克利福德·斯塔奇
Are you Clifford Stuckey?
-克利福德·斯塔奇吗  -是的
- Clifford Stuckey. - Yeah.
我们想请你去趟警局
We'd like you to come down
谈谈你家被闯入的案子
town as about your break-in.
大点声  小伙子
You'll have to speak up, son.
我把助听器掉到厕所里了
I dropped my hearing aid down the toilet.
贝克特会喜欢他的
Oh, Beckett's gonna love him.
什么
What?
斯塔奇先生  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Mr. Stuckey, I'm Detective Kate Beckett.
我到处惹麻烦的时候
I wish they had cops like you
怎么没见到你这样的警察
when I was getting in trouble.
先生  你能告诉我
Uh, sir, could you tell us
-你去卡福的办公室干嘛  -谁
- what you were doing in Mr. Carver's office? - Who?
迪昂·卡福  他是个保释代理人
Deon Carver. He was a bail bondsman.
他昨晚被谋杀了
He was murdered last night.
我们在他办公室找到了你的指纹
We found your fingerprints in his office.
他呀
Oh, him. Ah.
什么问题来着
What was the question?
卡福先生为兰登·皮尔斯负责保释
Mr. Carver posted bail for Random Pierce,
那个人闯入了你的家
the man who broke in to your apartment.
我要知道你为什么去他的办公室
I need to know what you were doing in his office.
你相信人老了就不能学新东西了吗  探长
Do you believe an old dog can learn new tricks, Detective?
不相信
No.
我也不相信
Ah, neither did I.
之后我就变老了
And then I got old.
跟你说
You see,
我这一生都不是什么好人
I-I been a bad man most of my life.
现在我的朋友不是死了就是在蹲监狱
And now all my friends are dead or in jail,
我就
And I got...
我就感觉生活没了意义
nothing to show for my... my time here.
斯塔奇先生  我在问卡福的办公室
Mr. Stuckey, Carver's office?
什么
Huh?
当警察告诉我
Oh. When the police told me that
是那个男孩闯进了我家
that boy had broken into my place,
突然间  我就看见了40年前的自己
well, suddenly, I-I saw myself 40 years ago,
我就想  如果那个时候能有人放我一马
and I thought, if somebody had just given me a break,
也许我的生活就会完全不同
maybe my life woulda turned out differently.
所以我就去找  叫什么来着  卡福
So--so I went to see what's his name--Carver?
我告诉他如果那个小子
And I told him that I would consider, you know,
保证他会改过自新
dropping the charges if that kid could convince me
不再犯错
that he was, you know,
我就会撤诉
willing to straighten his life out.
你昨晚在哪
Where were you last night?
在家睡觉  半睡半醒
At home asleep, or as close as I ever get...
每隔半个小时我都要小便
having to pee every half-hour.
你应该见识下我前列腺  小子
Oh, you should see the size of my prostate, son.
-只有婴儿拳头那么大  -好吧  算了
- It's like a baby's fist. - Yeah, whoa. Thank you.
-谢谢你  斯塔奇先生  -很好
- Thank you, Mr. Stuckey. - That's--that's good.
就是他  我在哪能找到他
Hey, that's the kid. Any idea where I can find him?
我还是可以撤诉的
My--my offer still stands.
抱歉  斯塔奇先生  太迟了
I-I'm sorry, Mr. Stuckey. It's too late.
他马上就要回到监狱了
He's already on his way back to jail.
晕
Aw, jeez.
算我多疑
Call me crazy,
我认为他看的不是兰登的照片
but I don't think he was looking at Random's picture.
他在偷瞄那个文件
It was like he was checking out that document.
你是说"世界上最无聊的涂鸦"么
Oh, you mean, "The world's least-interesting doodle"?
我正准备打开卡福的头颅
I was just getting ready to cut open Carver's skull
我看到了额头上的印记
When I saw it on his forehead.
什么印记
Saw what?
光线
The light has to be
一定要对好角度
at the right angle to catch the shine.
十字架的印记吗
The sign of the cross?
我查了下十字架是用什么物质画的
I ran a test on the substance the cross was drawn with.
-不是吧  -没错  圣油
- Don't tell me. - Yep, holy oil.
圣油
Holy oil?
看来凶手给卡福做了最后一次洗礼
Looks like our killer gave Carver last rites.
爸爸  再睡会  早饭马上好
Dad, go back to bed. Breakfast is almost ready.
亲爱的  先别做早饭了
Honey, stop cooking for a second.
我有话和你说
I want to talk to you.
我决定好给不给我买摩托车了
You've made a decision about the scooter?
你听说过富裕病吗
Have you ever heard of affluenza?
你是说流行性感冒[二者音似]
Uh, you mean influenza?
不是  富裕病  是一种
No, affluenza. It's a condition
有钱人家中的孩子经常得的一种病
that affects children who come from wealthy homes.
是你胡诌的吧
You're making that up.
不是  我在维基百科上看到的
I'm not. It's on wikipedia.
不能相信网上看到的所有东西
Can't believe everything you read online.
我知道  但是我要说的是
I don't, but the point is,
你是个好孩子
you're a great kid.
我是怕  如果我给你所有你想要的东西
I'm just afraid that if I just give you everything you want,
会扭曲你的金钱观
It's gonna warp your relationship with money.
这么说你不同意
So you're saying no?
不  不是  我是说
I--no, I'm not saying that. I'm--
我是说  如果你
I'm saying... that if you--
如果你真的觉得这很重要
If this is really important to you,
那么这个钱你就要自己赚
then you need to earn the money yourself.
我是说自己赚  不是让你让上大学的钱
And by earn, I don't mean raid your college fund.
-谢谢  -你为什么谢我
- Thank you. - Why are you thanking me?
因为你同意了
Because you said yes.
-我同意了吗  -你在想什么
- I did? - What are you thinking?
我认为她会退却的
That she would fold.
我们说的可是阿丽克西斯
This is Alexis we're talking about.
她从来就没遇到过她解决不了的难题
She has never met a challenge that she hasn't attacked
就像匈奴王一样不可战胜
like attila the hun.
但是  她根本就
Yeah, but it would take her so long--
不到一周她就能把钱弄到手
She'll have the money by next week.
你知道还有什么等着你吗
And then you know what you're in for?
纹身
You're in for tattoos.
鼻环
You're in for nose rings.
还有那些乱七八糟的东西
You're in for--oh, who knows what?
你的叛逆期有多疯狂
Just how wild was your wild-child phase?
你不想知道的
You don't want to know.
我可能找到了洗礼杀手的线索
So I might have a lead on our last rites killer.
死者财务报告显示他曾数次给一个
Our victim's financials show he made several donations
由艾伦·洛神父经营
to a church in the South Bronx
位于南布朗克斯的教堂捐过款
run by a father Aaron Low.
莱恩把他带过来了
Ryan's on his way to bring him in.
贝克特  他来了
Hey, Beckett. Yeah, he's here.
有流苏哦
No-hassle tassels.
你和迪昂·卡福
What was the nature of your
是什么关系
relationship with Deon Carver?
他是我教会的一员
He was a member of my congregation...
也是我的朋友
And friend.
两天前晚上9点到11点你在哪
Where were you 2 nights ago between 9:00 and 11:00?
我在教堂
I was at the church.
我们有个仪式  之后我就上床睡觉了
We had a late service, then I went home to bed.
很抱歉
Now I'm sorry.
我还有事  如果你们没别...
I have an appointment, so if you'll excuse me--
神父  那双可真是杀手鞋啊[双关  也指鞋子好看]
Whoa! Father, those are killer shoes.
很不走运  那双鞋和杀害卡福的凶手
Unfortunately, those are the same shoes that were worn
穿的是同一款鞋
by the man who killed carver,
我很确定  如果把你的鞋送去鉴证
And I'm certain that if we send those to the lab,
就会发现鞋底沾满了卡福的血
they'll have Carver's blood all over them.
听着  我去的时候迪昂就已经死了
Look, Deon was dead when I got there.
接着编
Try again.
我发誓我发现他躺在办公室
Look, I swear. I found him lying in his office.
我给他做了最后的洗礼  然后报了警
I administered last rites, and then I dialed 9-1-1.
打的是匿名电话  之后你就跑了
Anonymously, and then you ran.
我帮不上什么忙
There was nothing more I could do.
你为什么去他办公室
Why were you there in the first place?
迪昂的婚姻出了问题
Well, Deon was having marital troubles.
我在帮他找到方向
I was helping him find his way.
婚姻问题
Marital troubles?
你确定你不是去找这个吗
Are you sure that you didn't go there looking for this?
我不知道那是什么
I don't know what that is.
他还真是不会说谎
Lying is not his strong suit.
-牧师就应该这样  -我在说实话
- A quality I like in a priest. - I'm telling the truth.
神父  你离开一个犯罪现场
Father, you left the scene of a crime,
你自称死者是你的朋友
and a man that you describe as a friend was murdered.
如果你是清白的
If you didn't have anything to hide,
你就不会逃走
you would've stayed.
我被吓到了  那么多的血
Look, I was in shock. Okay? There was so much blood.
跑掉是我唯一的想法
All I could think to do was escape.
因为你杀了他
Because you murdered him.
不  是因为现场的情况
No! Because... Because of how it looked.
我见过的很多罪犯都和我说过
The convicts I work with tell me horror stories
警察会栽赃陷害
about the police, about how they're framed.
我发现迪昂死了  我...
You know, when I found Deon like that, I...
我慌了
I panicked.
这样确实很丢脸
Am I ashamed? Yes.
但你们得相信  我没有杀害任何人
But you have to believe, I didn murder anybody.
神父  请原谅
Father, you'll have to forgive me,
现在是谋杀案件调查
but this is a murder investigation.
信仰不能帮助我进行判断
And I can't base this on faith.
嘿
Hey.
嘿  看来你们抓到凶手了
Hey, it looks like you caught your killer.
也许吧
Yeah, maybe.
然后呢
So...
他是不是想用《僵尸启示录》来蛊惑你们啊
Was he trying to start the Zombie Apocalypse?
你就讽刺我吧
Mock all you want.
我们伟大的神父知道那张纸是干嘛的
Our good father knows what that paper is.
对了  兄弟  我在衣橱里找到张相片
Oh, man. Hey. I found this picture in my closet.
我猜你会很感兴趣
I thought you'd get a kick out of it.
哦  看看你  光彩夺目啊
Oh, look at you! All shiny and bright.
是不是要我把你养动物的丑事给抖出来啊
What did I tell you about feeding the animals?
听我说  我只是想对
Listen, I just stopped by
上次协助追捕逃犯的事再次表示感谢
to say thanks again for the bounty assist
另外  想请你吃顿午饭
and, uh, thought maybe I could buy you lunch.
好啊  没问题
Yeah, sure.
卡福办公室的那个窃听器是来自泰国
So it looks like the bug from Carver's office was shipped
在第五大道的一家间谍用品店有售
from thailand to a, uh, spy shop on fifth avenue.
猜猜看是谁买的
Guess who bought it.
费尔·艾伦
Faer Aaron.
布鲁克·卡福  死者的老婆
Brooke Carver, our victim's wife.
有趣  她可没说过
Funny. She failed to mention
她在窃听她老公的办公室
that she was bugging her husband's office.
那么也许神父没撒谎
And perhaps the good father
他们确实是要谈论婚姻问题
was telling the truth about Carver's marital problems.
都进行窃听了
Nothing says "Marriage on the rocks"
还不能说明婚姻破裂吗
like electronic eavesdropping.
但不能表明是她杀的啊
But does it say "Murder"?
问问她就知道了
Let's ask her.
要不  等我下班后你再过来吧
Oh, uh, why don't you stop by after my shift?
我请你喝一杯
I'll buy you a beer.
行
It's a date.
我们一直争吵
We've been fighting all the time.
有时候  他甚至夜不归宿
Some nights, he wouldn't come home...
他说他在办公室睡
And he said he was sleeping at the office,
但我不信
but I didn't believe him.
所以才买了窃听器
So I bought the bug.
你认为他在骗你
You thought he was cheating on you.
当你确实听出异样时
And when you heard him in action,
就决定杀了他
you decided to make yourself a widow.
不是的  一开始  我都不敢听
No, at first, I couldn't even bear to listen.
我无法忍受他和别的女人在一起
I couldn't bear to hear him with another woman.
最后  我让我妹妹和我一起听
And finally, I made my sister listen with me,
但我们听到的  不是他们上床
But what we heard... it wasn't sex.
而是迪昂在倾诉他有多爱我
It was Deon talking about how much he loved me
他又是多希望能挽救我们的婚姻
and how he prayed that he could save our marriage.
我哭了一晚上
I cried all night.
第二天早上  我就把接收器给扔了
And in the morning, I threw the receiver away.
-那是什么时候的事  -几星期前
- And when was that?  - A few weeks ago.
我们的关系刚刚有点和缓
We had just started to find our way back to each other,
结果他却死了
and now he's dead.
以后我就只能靠一盒骨灰来怀念他了
Soon all I'll have to remember him by is a box of ashes.
布鲁克的妹妹证实了她的说辞
Brooke's sister confirms her story.
有很多目击证人表明艾伦神父
We got about a dozen witnesses that put father Aaron
在卡福被杀之时即当晚10点在教堂
in church at 10:00 p.M. when Carver was killed.
我们又回到原点了
So we're back to square one.
不对  答案就在我们眼前
No, the answer is right here in front of us.
我感觉得到
I can feel it.
只是有些东西被我们忽视了
It's just that there's something that we're not seeing.
这其中必有蹊跷  只是我们没发现
There's a connection that we haven't made yet.
要把神父给放了吗
Do you want me to start processing the good father out?
不  他虽然有不在场证明
No, he might have an alibi,
但他确实是牵扯其中
but he's definitely involved somehow.
这上面说艾伦神父自愿
It says here that father Aaron volunteers
到五点监狱去工作
at Five Points correctional.
那是兰登待的那个监狱
That's where Random did his time.
他们互相认识
They knew each other.
而且还认识被害者
And they both knew our victim.
那么也许五点监狱是问题的关键
So maybe Five Points is our connection.
-斯塔奇有没有在那儿待过  -没
- Did Stuckey do time there?  - Nope.
该死
Damn.
但不能说就完全没关系了
Doesn't mean they're not connected in a different way.
监狱是罪犯们互相联系的宝地
Prison's a networking gold mine for criminals.
好奇一下  兰登牢友是谁啊
Out of curiosity, who was Random's cell mate?
马尔科姆·劳埃德
Uh, Malcolm Lloyd,
是个累犯小偷  因珠宝抢劫入狱20年
A recidivist thief doing 20 for a jewel heist.
我们应该找他谈谈
We should go talk to him.
不可能了  三星期前
Can't. Looks like he died of
他在监狱死于心脏病
a heart attack in prison three weeks ago.
若是艾伦神父
Wouldn't it be funny
为劳埃德主持最后的祷告
if father Aaron administered last rites
不是很有趣吗
for Lloyd as well?
莱恩
Ryan.
-在   -查一下劳埃德的已知联系人
- Yeah.  - Check Lloyd's known associates.
没有提到神父  等一下
Doesn't mention the priest. Wait a minute.
这上面说劳埃德认识克利福德·斯塔奇
It says Lloyd knew Clifford Stuckey.
貌似他和劳埃德
Looks like he and Lloyd
在同一件珠宝抢劫案中被捕
were both arrested for the same jewel heist.
他们是同伙
They were partners.
当时地方检察官没有足够的证据
D.A. didn't have enough evidence
来起诉斯塔奇
to prosecute Stuckey,
所以他逃脱了罪名而劳埃德却被判了20年
so he walked while Lloyd did 20 years.
那还是不能解释
That still doesn't explain
为什么兰登要闯入斯塔奇家
why Random broke in to Stuckey's apartment.
听听这个
Maybe this will help.
劳埃德和斯塔奇盗窃的珠宝
The heist that Lloyd and Stuckey pulled--
价值一千万美元的稀有蓝宝石和红宝石
$10 million in rare sapphires and rubies
猜怎么着
-and guess what.
仍然下落未明
They were never found.
伙计们
You guys...
我大概知道这是什么了
I think I know what this is.
是个寻宝图
It's a treasure map.
神父  我们和监狱核对过了
Father, we checked with the prison.
是你给马尔科姆·劳埃德做了最后的祷告
We know that you gave Malcolm Lloyd his last rites.
那时你发现了那幅地图
That's when you found out about the map.
我一直照料马尔科姆直到他死去
I ministered to Malcolm at the end.
他说他很害怕
He told me he was scared, that...
他想在死前做件好事
He wanted to do one good thing before he died.
他让我保证会将钱用于教会
He made me promise that I would use it for the church.
但当我找到牢房时  地图不见了
But when I went to the cell, um, the map wasn't there.
因为兰登已经拿走了
Because Random had already taken it.
而兰登出狱之后
But when Random got out of jail,
又找不到珠宝
he couldn't figure it out.
所以他闯进了斯塔奇家
So he breaks in to Stuckey's apartment,
企图以暴力强迫
figuring he's gonna
劳埃德的老搭档帮他
strong-arm Lloyd's old partner into helping him.
结果斯塔奇不在家
Only Stuckey wasn't home,
-而且还有人报了警  -是我报的警
- and someone called the cops.  - I called them.
我一直跟踪他  打算趁他被捕之际
I had been following Random. I knew that his arrest would
以此要挟他
give me the leverage I needed
和我共享地图的信息
to force him to share the map.
因为你和保释代理人是朋友
Because you were friends with the bail bondsman.
兰登付不起保释金
Look, Random had no money for bail.
迪昂同意保释他
Deon agreed to cover it
但要求分享三分之一的珠宝
for a third of the treasure,
他还坚持要保管地图
but he insisted on holding on to the map for safekeeping.
那卡福死的那晚  你到底是去他的办公室
So why were you really at Carver's office
干什么呢
the night he died?
迪昂打电话给我说他知道珠宝在哪儿了
Deon called me and told me he'd figured out the map.
但当我到那儿时  他已经死了
But when I got there, he was already dead,
被那老头子给杀死了
murdered by that old man.
-斯塔奇  -你怎么知道
- Stuckey.  - How do you know?
因为前一晚斯塔奇发现迪昂和兰登
Because Stuckey had caught Deon and Random
一起在密谋着什么
conspiring together the night before.
他说他等那笔钱已经等了20年了
He told them he had waited 20 years for that money,
还让他们24小时内交还地图
and they had 24 hours to give it back,
不然就会杀了他们
or bodies were gonna start dropping.
斯塔奇先生
Mr. Stuckey.
请跟我们走一趟
We need to talk.
这下完了  让他跑了
We're never gonna hear the end of this.
去他的
Aw, crap.
埃斯波西托和莱恩什么时候回来啊
When do Esposito and Ryan get back?
快了  他们正赶往中央监狱
Soon. They're on their way to Central Booking
去找兰登询问一下地图的事
to pick up Random to ask him about the map.
我打了几个电话问了下
So I made a couple of phone calls,
1990年被窃珠宝当时价值一千万美元
and this heist in 1990 was worth $10 million,
现在几乎翻了三倍
and now it's worth almost $30 million.
-可以走了吗  -可以啊
- Hey, you ready?  -Yeah.
什么  你现在还不能走啊
Uh, what? You can't leave now.
放松点  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
市里每个警员手上都有斯塔奇的照片
Every uniform in the city's got Stuckey's photo.
若说我的教官曾教过我什么的话
and if there's one thing that my T.O. taught me,
那就是有时候解决案子的最好办法
it's that sometimes the best way to crack a case
就是好好休息一下
is by taking a break.
我保证不会让她在外面待太久
Promise I won't keep her out too late.
那么  那个
So... it's...
其实是个藏宝图
actually a treasure map, huh?
卡塞尔研究了一整天
Castle's been trying to figure it out all day.
我应该早点盯上斯塔奇的
I should've been on to Stuckey earlier, though.
-没人是完美的  -你是啊
- Nobody's perfect.  - You were.
你太容易蒙了
You were easy to impress.
不  才不是
No, I wasn't.
我当时正沉溺于茫茫大海
I was drowning, and...
而你是那海中小岛
You were dry land.
学院只是教我们
All they ever taught us
如何做些文件工作
in the academy was how to do paperwork.
你却真正教会我如何当个警察
You were the one who taught me how to be a cop.
你是个聪明的学生
You were easy to teach.
想让你安稳老实点
Keeping you outta trouble?
可就没那么简单了
Mm. Not so much.
不老实  我吗
Oh, trouble? Me?
抢了杨克斯的骑自行车的小鸡那件事怎么说
What about that biker chick from Yonkers?
没错  但我不是让她做了指证吗
Yeah, well, I got her to snitch on her crew, didn't I?
却让我去做诱饵
By offering me up as man bait.
你该看看当她告诉法官
Oh, you shoulda seen your face
"他让我完满"时
when she told the judge,
-你的表情  -你太狠毒了
- "He completes me."  - That's mean.
我抓到他了  罗伊
I caught him, Royce.
那个杀害我母亲的的人
The man who killed my mom.
这么多年了
After all these years?
知道是为什么了吗
You find out why he did it?
是有人雇他杀的
Somebody paid him to do it.
但在找到幕后主使前我却必须向他开枪
But I had to shoot him before I could find out who.
真是太蠢了
That was stupid.
你该给他看下你的胸
You shoulda just shown him your boobs.
爸爸
Dad?
嘿
Hey.
你来这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
我弄到钱了
I got the money.
这么快
Already?
-对啊  -怎么弄的
- Mm-hmm.  - How?
卖光剑  我在淘宝上找到个人
The lightsabers. I found a guy on ebay
他愿意花2000美元买光剑
willing to pay 2 grand for them.
但那些玩意是我们的最爱啊
But we had so much fun with those.
我们一次拯救一个宇宙星系
We were saving the universe one galaxy at a time.
你就是因为那个而喜爱上击剑的
That's what got you into fencing.
我知道爸爸  但我已经玩厌了
I know, dad, but I've outgrown them.
哦  我想
No, I-I guess...
我想是的吧
I guess you have.
你生气了吗
Are you mad?
不  没有
No. No.
是这个案子
I--I'm frustrated
我有点摸不着头脑
over this case.
就是这个地图吗
Is that the map?
是啊  它让我怀疑我的高智商了
Yeah, and it's making me doubt my own genius.
有些东西我就是怎么想也想不透
There's just something I am not seeing.
能让我看一下吗
Can I take a look?
行啊
Sure.
它叠放在死者的袜子里
We found it folded up in our victim's sock.
-有好多折痕啊  -是啊
- It's got a lot of fold marks on it...  - Yeah.
就像个迷宫
Almost like a puzzle...
或是算命纸
Or one of those paper fortune-tellers.
或者是《疯狂》杂志
Or "Mad" magazine.
《疯狂》杂志曾把迷图印在背面
"Mad" Magazine used to have its trick picture on the back.
若折法正确
If you folded it the right way,
就能看到一幅完全不同的图画
it would show you an entirely different image.
看  那里  那里有个字
Hey, there's-- there's a word there.
在
"The."
下面
"Under."
下面  在下面
Under. "Under the..."
枪
"Gun."
在枪下面
"Under the gun."
-在枪下面  -在枪下面
- "Under the gun."  - "Under the gun."
那是  那是什么意思
What d-- what does at mean?
不知道
I don't know.
我得走了
I should get going.
他们应该快把兰登带到警局了
They're gonna be bringing Random into the precinct.
那我也去抓逃犯了
I'm just gonna hit the head.
我是莱恩  我们在中央拘留所
It's Ryan. We're at Central Booking.
兰登不在这儿
Random isn't here.
什么叫他不在那儿
What do you mean, he's not there?
那他在哪儿
Where is he?
不知道
I don't know.
你的罗伊兄弟没把他送过来
Your buddy Royce never delivered him.
他竟然骗了我
I can't believe he lied to me.
人是会为金钱而疯狂的
Money makes people do crazy things.
看看电视上那些
Look at any reality show contestant
吃蟑螂的真人秀选手就知道了
who ever ate a cockroach on television.
但这并不意味着他杀了卡福
Doesn't mean he killed Carver.
嗯  但在没找到其他嫌疑人之前
Yeah, well, until I find otherwise,
我只能设想是他做的
I'm gonna have to assume that he did.
你觉不觉得他来这儿是想
Do you think he came here
像斯塔奇一样看一下地图呢
to see the map like Stuckey did?
不可能  哦  糟了
No. Oh, no.
怎么了
What?
我给你们照相时
When I took the picture of the two of you,
你们正站在这板子前面
you were standing in front of the murder board.
也就是说他有地图了
He has a copy of the map.
是的  但显然  他解不开那个迷
Yes, but obviously, he can't figure it out.
所以他才过来  想看一下我们解开没
That's why he was here. He wanted to see if we did.
哟  贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
我将珠宝抢劫案的文件调了出来
I pulled the files from the jewelry heist.
罗伊也参与了调查行动
Your boy Royce was part of the investigation.
所以他一开始就知道宝藏的事了
So he knew about the treasure from the start.
我们已经派人监视他的寓所
We have surveillance on his apartment,
而且全面通缉他的车
And an A.P.B. Out on his car.
"枪下面"是什么意思  有任何头绪吗
What about "Under the gun"? Any idea what that means?
不  还没有  抢劫案地点的五个街区外
No, not yet. There was a gun club about five blocks
有一间枪支俱乐部  但是已经拆毁了
From the jewel heist, but it was torn down
十年前就被重建成公共设施了
And turned into condominiums about ten years ago.
那么好吧  继续找
All right, then. Keep looking.
是我
it's me.
罗伊  自首吧
Royce, turn yourself in.
我做不到  丫头
I can't do that, kid.
现在我快拿到钱潜逃了
I'm too close to the money to walk away right now.
听着  我只是  想让你知道
Listen, I just... Need you to know that I...
我并不是有意要这样走掉的
Didn't mean for it to go like this.
你杀了卡福是为了地图吗
Did you kill Carver for the map?
别这样  丫头  你了解我的
Oh, come on, kid. You know me better than that.
我不觉得
I don't think I do,
因为我认识的那个人不会这样背叛我
Because the man that I knew wouldn't betray me like this.
我要走了
I gotta go. I--
迈克
Mike...
我曾经爱上过你
I was in love with you.
噢  凯特  别这样
Oh, kate, don't.
你是唯一一个人
You were the only one
能懂得我作为动力的那股执着
Who understood the obsession that drove me...
是你跟我说
Who didn't tell me that
我无法释怀我母亲的死
I would get over my mother's murder
而她不会愿意看到我这样做
And that she wouldn't want me to do this.
我只是  只是想帮你一把  孩子
Just... Just trying to do right by you, kid.
我梦见过你
I dreamt about you.
那晚我向那个杀害我母亲的凶手开枪
The night that I shot the guy who killed my mother,
我希望躺在地上奄奄一息的人是我
I dreamt that I was the one who was on the ground dying,
然后你走过来
And that you came up to me
叫我坚强站起来
and told me to stand up
因为还有工作要做
'cause there was still work to be done.
我那天早上起床后
When I woke up that morning,
我只想打给你
I just wanted to call you,
但我们太久没有说过话了
But we hadn't talked in so long.
你应该打给我的
You shoulda called.
我从没忘记你
I never forgot you.
我会抓到杀害卡福的凶手的  罗伊
I'm going to catch Carver's killer, Royce.
然后我会找回劳埃德的宝藏
And then I'm going to recover Lloyd's score.
当我逮捕你的时候
And when I arrest you,
你会意识到你今天所摧毁的
You're gonna realize that what you destroyed today
比那笔臭钱更有价值
Was worth a hell of a lot more than money.
我拖住他的时间够长吗
Did I keep him on long enough?
嗯  嗯
Uh... Um...
是的  我们查到地址了
Yeah. We got an address.
好的  走吧
All right. Let's go.
那些全是为了要追查他的演技吗
Wh--all--all that was just an act to get a trace?
当然
Of course.
噢
Oh.
纽约警局
NYPD!
呜  感谢上帝
Whoo. Thank god.
-那兄弟绑架我  -安全
- That dude totally kidnapped me. - Clear.
省省吧  我们已经知道地图的事了
Knock it off. We already know about the map.
真的吗
Really?
-罗伊在哪里  -出去找我的钱了
- Where's Royce? - Out lookin' for my money.
看上去他背叛了我们所有人
Looks like he betrayed all of us.
兰登  你现在将事实告诉我们
Random, either you start telling us the truth,
要不埃斯波西托就将你
Or Esposito is gonna hang you out
倒着挂在窗外
that window by your feet.
看  我是受害者
Look, I'm a victim in all this.
我跟一个不肯住口的怪老家伙上下铺
I bunked with a geezer who wouldn't shut up
不停的说他得到的一千万  他怎样埋在
About his $10-million score, how he'd buried it
没人能找到的地方  除非有那张地图
Where nobody could find it, not without the map.
但后来我和卡福
But then I had to partner with Carver
还有那个神经兮兮的神父一伙
and the creepy priest,
我们没人能解开地图上的迷
And instead of us trying to figure out the map,
他们想做的只是争吵将卡福的老婆
All they wanted to do was argue about how unchristian
从中除掉有多不道德
it was to cut Carver's wife out of the score.
你们是在卡福的办公室里吵的吗
This argument, did it take place in Carver's office?
没错
Yeah.
布鲁克安装了窃听器的地方
Which Brooke had bugged.
-真的吗  -打给莱恩  叫他去找布鲁克
- Seriously? - Call ryan, have him find Brooke.
好的
Right.
她不是听到他对她永垂不朽的爱
She didn't hear him profess his undying love for her.
她听到他想将她从一千万除掉
She heard him trying to cut her out of millions.
然后她当着我们的面撒谎了
And then she lied to our faces.
婚姻触礁  地下的财富
Marriage on the rocks, a fortune in rocks--
两个强烈的杀人动机
Two strong motives for murder.
我们给她看过那张地图
We showed her the map.
难怪她的手直发抖
Well, no wonder her hands were trembling.
莱恩查到布鲁克在卡福的办公室
Ryan traced Brooke at Carver's office.
好的  走吧
All right. Let's go.
嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
那我怎么办
What about me?
吃个芝士泡芙  警员正赶过来
Have a cheese puff. Uniforms are on their way.
这里没人
there's no one here.
我们没抓到了她
We just missed her.
她想靠记忆把地图画出来
She was trying to recreate the map from memory.
看看这个  她从窃听器里
Look at this. Notes she took
听到的  所做的笔记
While she was listening in on the bug.
看看这里  在枪下面
Right here--"Under the gun."
她听到他们想出来了
She heard them figure it out,
但没有地图  她找不到宝藏
But without the map, she can't find the treasure.
因为那些钱可能埋在任何地方
That's because the score could be buried anywhere.
不  不可能
No, it can't be.
纽约基本上是一个混凝土的岛屿
New york is basically an island of concrete.
劳埃德必须确保他埋钱的地方
Lloyd would have to make sure he buried it someplace
不会被拆毁或者被挖掘去建造公寓
That couldn't be torn down or dug up to make condos.
可能在公园  或者墓地
The park maybe. Or a cemetery.
布鲁克不是说卡福是火葬的吗
Didn't Brooke say Carver was being cremated?
那么她为什么会有墓地指南
So why does she have cemetery brochures?
地图上的那些不是线
Those weren't lines on the map.
是墓碑
Those were gravestones.
要打赌是埋在枪的下面吗
Want to bet it's buried under the gun?
你知道  如果这是恐怖电影的话
You know, if this were horror movie,
我们会是第一个死的  像这样爆裂身亡
We'd be the first ones killed, splitting off like this.
没错  除了我们并不是恐怖电影里外出
Yeah, except we're not a couple of top-heavy coeds
寻欢作乐的小情侣
out looking for fun.
我们是经过严格训练的执法警官
We're highly trained officers of the law
而且有足够火力解决一大群的亡灵
With enough firepower to take out a horde of undead.
自大的西班牙人  你肯定是先死的那一个
Hispanic and cocky. Yeah, you definitely die first.
你知道  如果这是恐怖片
You know, if this was a horror movie--
卡塞尔  专心点
Castle, focus.
哈  就是那个  看
ha! There it is. There it is. Look.
好的
Ok.
没错
Yes!
看来已经有人来过这里了
looks like someone's been here already.
把枪丢了
drop the gun.
-我不能那样做  -那咱们就有麻烦了
- I can't do that. - Then we got a problem.
你不会杀警察的  布鲁克
You're not a cop killer, Brooke.
我知道你不是故意要杀迪昂
I know you didn't mean to kill Deon.
他只是在你
He just surprised you
找地图的时候出现了而已
when you were looking for that map.
见鬼去吧  我是有意杀他的
To hell with that. Of course I meant to kill him.
我忍受了他十年的
After ten years of putting up with
恋脚癖和打鼾声
His foot fetish and snoring,
他就这样背叛我吗
he betrays me like that?
那宝藏是我应得的
Unh-unh. I deserve that treasure,
我一定要把它带走
And I'm not leaving here without it.
唯一能带走宝藏的是我
The only one leaving with that treasure is me.
而且我拿着最大的枪
And I got the biggest gun.
不再是了  老头子
Not anymore, grandpa.
纽约警局  现在丢下你的武器
NYPD! Drop your weapon right now!
快丢下  纽约警局
Drop it! NYPD!
快丢下  笨蛋  你有什么毛病
Drop it, stupid. What's wrong with you?
现在丢下你的武器  现在丢下
Drop your weapon right now! Drop it now!
罗伊  怎么样
What about you, Royce?
你要为了宝藏向我开枪吗
You willing to shoot me for that treasure?
可能你没注意  丫头
In case you haven't noticed, kid,
我的枪口并不是对着你
My gun's not pointed at you.
我的是  在这个射程
Well, my gun is, and at this range,
我会将她还有那男的打个稀巴烂
I'm gonna turn her and the haircut into soup.
你敢开枪  你就死定了  老头
You shoot, you die, gramps.
你觉得我在意吗
You think I care?
唯一让我生存的理由
The only thing that's keeping me alive
就是那石头下的一千万  我要不就
Is that $10 million in stones. Either I
带着钱走  或者被装在装尸袋里走
leave with it, or I leave in a body bag.
那么或者在我们开枪前
Well, then maybe we should make sure
得先确定那些钱还在这里
That treasure's even there before we start shooting.
卡塞尔  介意吗
Castle, do you mind?
为什么是我
Why me?
因为你是这里唯一没有枪的人
Because you're the only one without a gun.
有道理  好吧
Good point. Okay.
只是  呃
Just, uh...
你跟他有计划吗  丫头
You got a plan he, kid?
无可奉告
Not one that I'm ganna share with you.
或者这是你表现的机会了
Maybe you should show us all something.
嘿
Hey.
嘿  伙计
Hey, guys.
我想我找到些东西
I think I found something.
就像从前  哈  丫头
Just like old times, huh, kid?
放下枪  快点
Drop the gun. Now.
宝藏  让我看看宝藏
The treasure. Let me see the treasur
我只是想分散你的注意力
Yeah, I j--I just said that to distract you.
如果不这样的话  我就会秀咪咪了
It was either that or show 'em my boobs.
你拿下罗伊了吗
You got Royce?
没错
Yeah.
-起来  起来  -莱恩
- Get up. Get up. - Ryan.
是的
Yeah.
好的  过来  站起来
All right, come on. on your feet.
走吧  你抓住他了吗  快走
Let's go. You got him? Move.
没错
yeah.
来吧  丫头
Go ahead, kid.
做你要做的事
Do what you gotta do.
迈克尔·罗伊  你被逮捕了
Michael Royce, you're under arrest.
呃
Uh...
哈喽
Hello?
没有人想看看这里是不是真有宝藏吗
Doesn't anyone want to see if there actually is a treasure?!
我不相信那里真的没有宝藏
I can't believe there wasn't actually a treasure.
或者我们把地图理解错了
Maybe we read the map wrong.
或者这全是徒劳的搜索
Maybe it was all a wild goose chase.
不管怎样  案子结了
Either way, case is closed.
嘿  贝克特怎么样
Hey, how's Beckett holding up?
偶像幻灭的滋味不好受啊
Hard to see your heroes fall.
嘿
Hey.
我能不能说一句
Can I just say
这真的很憋屈
How... Unsatisfying it is
去寻宝却没有宝藏
to go on a treasure hunt with no treasure?
那不是真正的寻宝  卡塞尔
Well, it wasn't really a treasure hunt, Castle.
这是凶杀案调查
It was a murder investigation.
噢  你不能否认
Oh, come on. You can't tell me
你没有一点点兴奋
You weren't just a little bit excited.
可能有一点
Maybe a little.
嗯
Mm.
真正困扰我得的是
What's bugging me, though, is,
如果没有宝藏  为什么还要画地图
If there was no treasure, then why make a map?
那是个大墓地
Well, it's a big cemetery.
有可能他画错了地点
Maybe he got the spot wrong.
或者在枪下面只是要误导我们
Or maybe "Under the gun" Was just to throw us off.
如果是我的话
You know, if it was me,
我会留些线索在地图以外
I would've left something out of the map,
最后一步
last step.
那么你觉得还有另一张地图了
So you think there was another map?
不  我会把线索随时带在身上
No, I would've kept it somewhere close to me,
某个只有我知道的地方
Somewhere where-- where only I knew that--
只有我知道它的重要
That it was important.
像是在我自己身上
Somewhere like on my body.
你觉得这是地图的最后一部分吗
Do you think this is the final part of the map?
还有其他东西重要得
What else would be important enough
让我们的珠宝大盗纹在自己手上吗
for our jewel thief to tattoo it on his arm?
好的  罗马数字  二在四上面
Okay, uh, roman numerals-- ii over a vi.
这意思就是  在我们挖掘的地方
I'm gonna say that that means two rows up,
再向上两排  六个墓碑以外的地方
Six stones over from where we dug.
你
You...
要去挖些什么吗  探长
Care to do some digging, detective?
你找到了吗
Well, did you find it?
没错  我们找到了
Yes, we did!
太棒了
Yay!
没错  不幸的是
yes. Unfortunately,
当你跟一个警察去寻宝
When you go treasure hunting with a cop,
她会确保
She makes you return
你将宝藏物归原主
the treasure to its rightful owner.
但是  呃  这晚上并没有完全失败
But, uh, well, the evening wasn't a total loss.
我们找到的时候
When we found it,
她给了我一个拥抱
she did give me a sweaty hug.
老爸
Dad.
那么你们俩在干嘛呢
So what are you girls doing?
在替你亮闪闪的新摩托车选颜色吗
You picking out a color for your shiny new scooter?
告诉他吧
Tell him.
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
我决定不买摩托车了
I decided not to get the scooter.
我一离开小区就意识到
I realized once I left the precinct
我要卖掉那些激光剑是个多错误的决定
How wrong it was for me to sell those lightsabers.
但我被摩托车给迷住了
But I was so caught up in wanting the bike
我说服自己
That I convinced myself
我只是一件商品去交易成另一件
I was just trading one thing for another.
但跟你玩星球大战的游戏
But playing pretend with you
是我童年时光最棒的回忆
Was one of the best parts of my childhood,
这对我来说
And it means more to me
比一辆亮闪闪的新摩托车重要的多
than a shiny new scooter ever could.
我替你感到骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
那足够买给我一辆新摩托车吗
Proud enough to buy me a new scooter?
不
No.
我做了个不可毁约的交易
I made a deal, and it would be wrong to break it.
但交易里没有任何条款
But there's nothing in that deal
禁止我自己去买一辆摩托车
that prohibits me from buying myself a scooter
或者可以让你隔三差五借用一下
and maybe letting you borrow it from time to time.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
当然  我可以送你去商店
Sure. I can send you to the store
-买激光剑的电池  -谢谢你  老爸
- For batteries for the lightsabers. - Thanks, dad.
噢  那要是你有了摩托车
Oh, and when you have the scooter,
我就能借你的汽车开了
maybe I can borrow the car.